



www.yazdipour.com

yazdipour@outlook.com linkedin.com/in/yazdipour/ Skype: sh.yazdipour

Profile

Shahriar (Sha) spent the past two years getting his Computer Science MSc in TU Ilmenau and also working as a JAVA Back-end Software Developer in TomTom Berlin. Dealing with Machine Learning projects in Academia and Backend Service Development is his current job. Previously, he spent 1.5 years as an Android Developer at a startup. Also he develops open source C# apps and study Blockchain and Solidity in his free time.

EDUCATION

Masters, Computer Science & Systems Engineering

Technische Universitat Ilmenau Thuringia, Germany

2019 - 2022

Kharazmi University Tehran, Iran

Bachelor, Computer Science 2013 - 2018

WORK EXPERIENCE

• BackEnd Software Engineer Intern at 'TomTom' - Berlin, Germany:

Aug 2020 - Now

- Main Task: Delivering services in the field of traffic information, tested and applied in the real-production system.
- o Working in Agile environment with daily standups and Jira Kanban discussions.
- o Programming a Java Spring REST API Service with Protobuf for TPEG2-EVA.
- o Developing Java Quarkus MQTT Pub/Sub Service for TPEG2-EAW.
- o Customizing and deploying VernemQ MQTT Broker.
- o Deployment on Microsoft Azure Cloud and Kubernetes. (Write ARM Templates, Working with Helm Charts, Working with ACR, AKS, App Services, Logic App, Azure DNS & Storage and SFTP Servers).
- Android Software Engineer at 'GFPishro Co' Tehran, Iran:

Oct 2017-Jan 2019

- Main Task: Creating a Geo Information Service/Software-Package, including Web, Desktop and Mobile applications for our customer.
- Developing Java / Android Mapping system based on MapsForge renderer system, graphhopper offline navigation for our customers using IntrAnet.
- Developing Simple Reporting Application for Client in iOS Xamarin Forms with C#.
- Using Visual Studio App Center for CI/CD pipeline.

SKILLS & EXPERIENCES

• Programming Languages:

- **Python** (PyTorch, Huggingface, Keras, Flask, PyAutoGui, MLFlow, ...)
- Java (Quarkus, Spring, Android, Swing,...)
- ∘ **C**# (Xamarin, UWP, WPF, .NET,...)
- Web (HTML, CSS, Basic VueJS, ¡Query)
- Blockchain (Solidity, Web3.py, Brownie)
- Tools: Git, Microsoft Azure, Docker, Kubernetes, Helm, Arm Template
- Databases/QLs: MySql, SQLite, Neo4j, SparQL, PostgreSQL

• Text-to-SPARQL Question Answering Transformer (NL2Script):

Aug 2021

- Task: Implementation of sentence embedding for learning the transformation of questions to SPARQL queries with DBPedia - WikiData data integration in Google T5 and BERT Transformer.
- o Pre-processing and collecting a data-set with specific features needed.
- o Implement Fine Tuning steps for T5 Language model using Pytorch.
- Developing a pipeline from data to deploying the model to Huggingface repositories.

• Covid-19 Opinion Leaders on Twitter - Data Mining and Graph Analysis:

Sep 2020

- o Task: Identifying opinion leaders in Twitter using social network Graph Analysis methods.
- Pre-processing 300GB twitter data-set with specific features using Dask.py (parallel computing library).
- Using Social network analysis methods to find opinion leaders with NetworkX Python library.

• Developed MIRA Robot navigation system:

Dec 2019

- o OpticalFlow and Color Segmentation Navigation using its camera system with C++
- o Object Detection using ResNet, ImageNet architecture with Pytorch

Recommendation System for Student Applicants, Seeking Financial Scholarship for Studying Abroad:

2017

- We have implemented a technique to bypass vBulletin CMS authentication system to crawl unstructured raw data from it and provide a dataset
- Using data analysis methods such as Decision tree, K-Nearest Neighbor and K-Means to determine chance of getting fund for graduate students.

Wireless Garage Door Cracker

Capturing sub-1 GHz signals with RTL-SDR and Analyzing with GQRX and sending signals with YardStick1.

Jul 2017

• UWP/WPF Applications (First Persian UWP Developer):

2015 - 2016

- Developed iTehran which is the First Persian UWP application.
- Developed multiple WPF and UWP application with more than 30,000 users download overall.
- Used MVVM, Xaml and C# to design Desktop and Mobile friendly applications.
- o Designed UI and Logo using Adobe XD and Photoshop.

Publications

Github Data Exposure using GraphQL Security Design Flaw (1k\$ Bug Bounty)

2019

S. Yazdipour*, CCSE2020 - The 10th International Conference on Computer Engineering, Ilmenau Germany

[Published]

Decision Support for International Students Who Want to Fund Their Graduate Studies

2017

S. Yazdipour*, N. Taherian "(IEEE) International Conference on Machine Learning and Data Science, India"

[Published]

CERTIFICATIONS (GITHUB.COM/YAZDIPOUR/CERTIFICATES)

- Microservices Foundations from Lynda
- Blockchain: Solidity by LinkedIn
- Structuring Machine Learning Projects-Coursera
- NLP with Python by Lynda

- Web Security by Shahid Beheshti University
- Al Foundations by Lynda
- Python 3 by Udemy
- CCNA by CyberTech